<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="12"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications



                          Mathematics in Geomatics Engineering: Application to Code Generation of GNNS Satellites

                                                              1*
                                                 Hassan Emami , Amir Bagheri  2

                 1  Department of Geomatics, Marand Faculty of Engineering, University of Tabriz, Tabriz-Iran, h_emami@tabrizu.ac.ir,
                                           h_emami@ut.ac.ir, ORCID: 0000-0002-0171-6487.

                2  Department of Basic Sciences, Marand Faculty of Engineering, University of Tabriz, Tabriz-Iran, a_bageri@tabrizu.ac.ir
              Abstract

                     This work demonstrates a realistic application of mathematics in the Geomatics and engineering. Mathematics
              and  engineering  work  together  as  they  are  right  hand  to  each  other  because  mathematics  is  the  bone  structure and
              engineering is the physical body. The Global Navigation Satellite System (GNSS) uses of satellites to provide autonomous
              Geo-spatial positioning. GNSS satellites continuously transmit signals at two or more frequencies. These signals contain
              Pseudorandom noise (PRN) codes and navigation data to allow users to compute both the travel time from the satellite to
              the receiver and the satellite coordinates at any time. The PRN codes are an important element of code division multiple
              access (CDMA) based satellite navigation systems. Each satellite within a GNSS constellation has a unique PRN code that
              it transmits as part of the C/A navigation message. This code allows any receiver to identify exactly which satellite(s) it is
              receiving. The PRN codes have special mathematical properties which allow all satellites to transmit at the same frequency
              without interfering with each other. These code also allow precise range measurements between satellite and user receivers.
              PRN codes generator contains two shift registers known as gold polynomials. In this research, PRN codes generation of
              GNNS Satellites using different polynomials is presented and discussed.

                            Keywords: Global Navigation Satellite System, Applied mathematics, Geomatics, PRN codes.

              1.  Introduction
                    Mathematics is defined as the study of quantities and relations with the help of numbers and symbols. So, mathematics
              and engineering work together as they are right hand to each other because engineering uses mathematical operations in the
              calculation  of  their  projects.  Mathematics  is  the  mother  of  all  sciences  and  engineering.  Also,  we  can  strongly  say  that
              mathematics is the bone structure and engineering is the physical body [1]. It is a powerful language, which we use to describe
              models  in  engineering,  and  also  in  other  sciences.  Furthermore,  mathematics  in  engineering  is  focuses  on  applications  of
              mathematics to science and engineering.  In contrast, Geomatics engineering is a specialized segment of engineering, focuses on
              the monitoring, implementation, and maintenance of global geospatial information. Geospatial information is any information
              that has positioned attributes associated with it. Geomatics engineering focuses on spatial information (i.e. information that has
              a location). The location is the primary factor used to integrate a very wide range of data for spatial analysis and visualization.
              The satellite navigation (SATNAV) systems are a branch of Geomatics engineering. These systems, uses of satellites to provide
              autonomous Geo-spatial positioning. Today, there are numerous SATNAV systems operating around the world. Some are global
              and others only provide service within a certain region. The term Global Navigation Satellite System (GNSS) is defined as the
              collection of all SATNAV systems and their augmentations [2]. The GNSS systems are the U.S. Global Positioning System
              (GPS), the Chinese BeiDou Navigation Satellite System (BDS), the European Galileo system, the Russian Federation GLObal
              Navigation Satellite System (GLONASS),  India’s Navigation with Indian Constellation (NavIC), and Japan’s Quasi-Zenith
              Satellite System (QZSS) [3, 4]. The GNSS includes constellations of Earth orbiting satellites that broadcast their locations in
              space and time, networks of ground control stations, and the receivers that calculate ground positions by trilateration. Figure 1
              shows four popular GNSS systems.

                    Positioning by GNSS systems is based on a very simple principle. However, a very high level of technological skill is
              required to make it work. The satellites send an electromagnetic signal and the user has a receiver equipped with a clock. The
              position of the satellites        known at each instant of time. The position    of the receiver is unknown. We begin by considering






                                                                                                              1]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications


              the ideal case: The satellite    1  sends a signal at time    1   and it is received at    at time    2 . The receiver   , using its clock which
              measures    1  and the message sent by    1  at time    2 , obtains the time ∆   1 =    1 −    2 , which corresponds to the distance    1 :

                                            = ‖       ‖ ∶          ∆     = ‖       ‖                                          (1)























                                        Figure 1. Earth orbiting of four famous GNSS systems [5].

                    The point    is thus located on the sphere ∑  of radius    1  centered on    1 . Likewise, the satellite    2  sends a signal, and
                                                     1
              by measuring the time interval∆   2 , this tells us that    lies on the sphere ∑  of radius    2  centered on    2 . The point    is thus on
                                                                      2
              the intersection of the spheres ∑  and∑ , which is a circle. With the satellite   3 , we obtain a third sphere ∑ , whose intersection
                                      1     2                                                 3
              with  ∑ ∩ ∑   gives just two points. One of these two points is therefore true location   .  In this ideal case, three satellites
                    1    2
              therefore suffice to locate   . However, to achieve this, the clock at    would have to have the same quality as those carried
              aboard the satellites, and this would be impossible because such clocks are cumbersome and very expensive. A fourth satellite
              is thus needed to make up for the inaccuracy of this clock. Figure 2 shows the basic principle of GNSS positioning. With known
              position of four satellites            and signal travel distance     , the user position can be computed.
                                                              




















                                         Figure 2. The basic principle of GNSS positioning [4, 6]
                    A GNSS signal is transmitted from a satellite in order to measure the distance between the satellite and a receiver. Each
              GNSS has its signal transmitted on specific radio frequencies. The GNSS satellites continuously transmit signals at two or more
              frequencies in the L band [7]. These signals contain ranging codes and navigation data to allow users to compute both the travel

                                                                                                             2]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications


              time from the satellite to the receiver and the satellite coordinates at any time. The main signal components, including: Carrier
              wave: Radio frequency sinusoidal signal at a given frequency [7, 8]. Ranging code: Sequences of zeroes and ones which allow
              the receiver to determine the travel time of the radio signal from the satellite to the receiver. They are called pseudo random
              noise (PRN) sequences or PRN codes[9]. PRN codes have random noise characteristics, but are precisely defined. They are a
              sequence of zeroes and ones, each zero or one referred to as a “chip”. Navigation data: A binary-coded message providing
              information  on  the  satellite  ephemeris,  clock  bias  parameters,  almanac,  satellite  health  status  and  other  complementary
              information. Figure 3 shows three main signal components of GNSS satellites.

















                                      Figure 3. Three main signal components of GNSS satellites [10].

                    The PRN codes have special mathematical properties which allow all satellites to transmit at the same frequency without
              interfering with each other. These codes also allow precise range measurements between satellite and user receivers. Figure 4
              shows a short repeating PRN code sample.










                                           Figure 4. A short repeating PRN code sample [11].


              2.  The Research Method

                    GPS, is one of the famous four GNSS systems. The four global GNSS systems are – GPS (US), GLONASS (Russia),
              Galileo (EU), BeiDou (China) [12]. To the all GNSS systems, the structure of the PRN code generation is conceptually similar,
              while, the form of using mathematical equations in the production of these codes is slightly different. GPS is the first of a new
              generation of GNSS systems. There are two different PRN code strings used by the GPS. They are the Coarse Acquisition Code
              (C/A-code), sometimes called the “Civilian Code,” and the Precise, or Protected Code (P-Code) [6]. The C/A code is a particular
              series of ones and zeroes, but the rate at which it is generated is 10 times slower than the P-Code. The C/A code rate is 1.023
              million bits per second. Here, satellite identification is quite straightforward. Not only does each GPS satellite broadcast its own
              completely unique 1023 bit C/A code, it repeats its C/A code every millisecond. The PRN code sequences are used as part of
              the Code-division  multiple  access (CDMA) scheme  in  GPS  [13].  (CDMA  is  a channel  access  method used  by
              various radio communication technologies). The PRN code don’t just use any random number. In fact, it’s not random, it’s a
              kind of pseudo-random number. A signal that’s statistically random doesn’t repeat itself at any point in its sequence and so it has
              very good autocorrelation properties. We also want the different codes for each satellite that are nearly orthogonal so the cross
              correlation of one code will be very high even when many satellite codes are mixed in. This is the scheme used to create pseudo-
              random sequences with all these properties for GPS and other GNSS satellites.



                                                                                                             3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications


                    PRN or the C/A code generator contains two shift registers known as Gold polynomial 1 (G 1) and Gold polynomial 2 (G 2),
              which  are  known  to  Gold  code  [14].  A Gold  code,  also  known  as Gold  sequence,  is  a  type  of  binary sequence,  used
              in telecommunication (CDMA) and  GNSS  satellites.  Gold  codes  are  named  after  Robert  Gold. Gold  codes  have  bounded,
              small cross-correlations within a set, which is useful when multiple devices are broadcasting in the same frequency range. A set
                                          n
                                                                          n
              of Gold code sequences consists of 2  + 1 sequences each one with a period of 2  − 1. A set of Gold codes can be generated with
                                                                          n
              the following steps. Pick two maximum length sequences of the same length 2  − 1 such that their absolute cross-correlation is
              less than or equal to 2 (n+2)/2 , where n is the size of the linear feedback shift register used to generate the maximum length sequence
              (Gold '67). The set of the 2  − 1 exclusive-OR of the two sequences in their various phases together with the two maximum
                                   n
                                      n
              length sequences form a set of 2  + 1 Gold code sequences. The highest absolute cross-correlation in this set of codes is 2 (n+2)/2  +
              1 for even n and 2 (n+1)/2  + 1 for odd n [14]. The exclusive OR of two different Gold codes from the same set is another Gold code
              in some phase. Within a set of Gold codes about half of the codes are balanced – the number of ones and zeroes differs by only
              one. The sequence would have 512 ones and 511 zeroes, and these would appear to be distributed at random.

              3.  The Gold codes and their properties
                    The  Gold  codes  are  selected  as  spreading  sequences  for  the  GPS  signals  because  of  their  characteristics.  The  most
              important characteristics of the C/A codes are their correlation properties [15]. A general PRN code can be seen as an infinite
              sequence of independent, identically distributed, random binary variables taking one of two values (0 or 1) with equal probability.
              The shift register can be described as Equation 2:

                                             y(n) =   h   y(n − k),                                   (2)

                    where m is the number of adders, and h    can take either of two values, 1 or 0, where 0 would indicate an absence of the
              corresponding adder in the shift register. In polynomial form, the shift register can be expressed as Equation 3:


                                             G(X) =   X                                                  (3)

                    The essential qualities of the PRN sequences are defined by the correlation measures. Two infinite random sequences
              should be uncorrelated. The closer a given PRN sequence comes in a truly random sequence, the better the PRN sequence is.
              The correlation between two sequences x(k) and z(k) is described by the following Equation 4:

                                                 1
                                           R(n) =    y(k)  z(n + k)                                   (4)
                                                 N

                    Moreover, a random sequence would have very specific autocorrelation properties, i.e. a random code would correlate
              with its own replica at only one point. The autocorrelation function can be found as a result of the multiplication of the sequence
              and its own shifted version as Equation 5:

                                                 1
                                           R(n) =    y(k)  y(n + k)                                   (5)
                                                 N

                    where N is the sequence period. The PRN codes are generated by a deterministic system and have finite length. In general,
              PRN codes are almost orthogonal to each other. In other words, they are almost uncorrelated. The orthogonal codes also have an
              autocorrelation function, with a single correlation peak. Gold codes are not orthogonal, but they guarantee uniformly low cross-
              correlation properties with other Gold codes. This property is very important for GPS signals, because all satellites transmit on
              the same frequency. Gold codes are short, with a maximum length of 1023 chips. The GPS satellite uses a 10.23 MHz onboard
              satellite clock to generate signals on all frequencies. The L1 C/A code is of 1 ms duration. The chip rate is therefore 1023
              chips/ms.
                     Furthermore, the Gold Codes are generated using a pair of shift registers (gold polynomials) with feedback. A shift
              register is just a list of bits that has an input end and an output end. The GPS registers are length 10. We’ll start them out with
              all 1’s, calculate the feedback, and then shift all the numbers over to the right. Gold codes are used the GPS C/A ranging codes
              are Gold codes of period 1,023 [11]. Every 1023rd period, the shift registers are reset with all ones, making the code start over.
                                                                                                             4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications


              After code generation, the codes are combined with the navigation data through Gold polynomial 2 adders. The exclusive OR
              operation is used on binary sequences represented by 0’s and 1’s, and its properties are shown in Table 1. If the binary sequences
              were represented by the polar non-return-to-zero representation, i.e., 1’s and −1’s, ordinary multiplication could be used instead.
              The corresponding properties of the multiplication with two binary non-return-to-zero sequences are shown in Table 1.
                                     Table 1. Output of the exclusive OR operation and ordinary multiplication.














                      This entire sequence of 1,023 chips is repeated 1,000 times each second, resulting in a “Chip-Rate” of 1.023 MHz or
              one phase switch (chip) every one-millionth of a second. Each satellite carries its own unique code string. The C/A code is the
              code used for the Standard Positioning Service (SPS).

                     The C/A code  generator contains two  shift registers  known as G    and G   . These shift registers each have 10 cells
              generating sequences of length 1023. The G    register always has a feedback configuration with the polynomial as Equation 6:


                                             G   :   F(X) = 1 + X + X                         (6)
                     This meaning that state 3 and state 10 are fed back to the input. Figure 5 show Gold polynomial (G1) shift register
              generator configuration.




























                                  Figure 5. Gold polynomial (G1) shift register generator configuration [14]

                     Therefore, only the delay between the polynomials matters in this case, because the sequence repeats itself. The delay
              is set by choosing specific tap outputs and combining them with exclusive OR operation, as shown in Table 1.  In the same way,
              the G    register has the polynomial as Equation 7:





                                        G   :   F(X) = 1 + X + X + X + X + X + X             (7)

                                                                                                             5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications


                     The C/A codes are generated at the rate of 1023 chips/ms. The shift registers, which are used for code generation, can
              be described by polynomials. The initial states of the polynomials and the phase between them define the code for a specific
              satellite. The initial states for both polynomials are set to the same value, i.e. 1:
                                                     (0) = {1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1 ,1 ,1, 1,1 }
                                            G    (0) = G
                     Figure 6 show Gold polynomial (G 2) shift register generator configuration.























                                 Figure 6. Gold polynomial (G 2) shift register generator configuration [11, 16].

                     The G 1 and G 2 registers are clocked at a 1.023 MHz rate. Thirty-six of the possible combinations over GPS satellites
              can be selected. Figure 7 show the combinations of GPS satellites for C/A code generation.



























                                     Figure 7. Combinations of GPS satellites for C/A code generation

                     As Figure 7 shows, there is a unique combination for each satellite to generate the C/A code. For example, satellite
              number 23 uses the combination of power 1 and power 3 of the second polynomial (G   ), and also for satellite number 16,
              combinations 9 and 10 are used. A Boolean operator working on two variables that has the value of one if one but not both of
              the variables has a value of one. To make different C/A codes for the satellites, the output of the two shift registers (G    and G   )

                                                                                                             6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications


              are combined in a very special manner. The G    register always supplies its output, but the G    register supplies two of its states
              to a modulo-2 adder to generate its output. The selection of states for the modulo-2 adder is called the phase selection. Moreover,
              a shift register is a set of one bit storage or memory cells. When a clock pulse is applied to the register, the content of each cell
              shifts one bit to the right. The content of the last cell is “read out” as output. The special properties of such shift registers depend
              on how information is “read in” to cell 1. For a tapped linear feedback shift register, the input to cell 1 is determined by the state
              of the other cells. For example, the binary sum from cells 3 and 10 in a 10-cell register could be the input. If cells 3 and 10 have
              different states (one is 1 and the other 0), a 1 will be read into cell 1 on the next clock pulse. If cells 3 and 10 have the same state,
              0 will be read into cell 1. If we start with 1 in every cell, 12 clock pulses later the contents will be 0010001110. The next clock
              pulse will take the 1 in cell 3 and the 0 in cell 10 and place their sum (1) in cell 1. Meanwhile, all other bits have shifted cell to
              the right, and the 0 in cell 10 becomes the next bit in the output.
                     The other G    polynomial has cells 2, 3, 6, 8, 9, and 10 are tapped and binary-added to get the new input to cell 1. In this
              case, the output comes not from cell 10 but from a second set of taps. Various pairs of these second taps are binary-added. The
              different pairs yield the same sequence with different delays or shifts. The delayed version of the G     sequence is binary-added
              to the output of G   . There are actually 37 PRN C/A codes, but two of them (34 and 37) are identical. A subset of the first 32
              codes are assigned to (nominally 24) satellites and recycled when old satellites die and new satellites are launched. Codes 33
              through 37 are reserved for other uses, including ground transmitters. Each of the first 32 segments is associated with a different
              satellite. The P code generation follows the same principles as the C/A code, except that 4 shift registers with 12 cells are used.
              The code is combined with the binary navigation data using modulo-2 addition: If the code chip and the data bite are the same
              (both are 0s or both are 1s), the result is 0; and if both are different, the result is 1. The composite binary signal is then impressed
              upon the carrier in a process called modulation. The combination of two polynomials and the generation of C/A code are shown
              together in Figure 8.































                                                    Figure 8. C/A code generation [17].

                     It  is  necessary  to  mention  PRN  sequences  or  C/A  codes  33  through  37  are  reversed  for  other  users  (e.g.  ground
              transmitters). Let us take a quick look at two special properties of PRN sequences which values ∓1.  Frist. PRN sequences are
              nearly orthogonal to each other: The sum to the term-by-term products of the two sequences, shifted arbitrarily relative to each
              other, is nearly zero. For two GNSS satellites k and l , which are assigned unique PRN sequences C/A codes x ( )  and x (  )  as
              Equation 8.




                                                                                                             7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications



                                              ( )
                                       x ( ) (i)  x (i + n) ≅ 0 ,     for all n, k  ≠ l                                   (8)

                     Where x (∎) (1023 + m) = x (∎) (m). The left side of Equation 8 defines the cross-correletion function of the the two
              sequenses for shift n . The orthooghonality of these codes allowes all GNSS satillaties to broadcast simultananeouslely at the
              same frequency without interfreing with each other [17].
                     The second important property is that a PRN seqence is nearly uncorrelated with itself, except forzero shift. for a C/A
              code as Equation 9.

                                               ( )
                                       x ( ) (i)  x (i + n) ≅ 0 ,     for all |n| ≥ 1                                   (9)

                     The left-hand side of Equation 9 defines the auto-correlation function of a sequence for shift n. The auto-correlation
              function of a PRN is nearly zero except for zero shift where it has a sharp peak. The cross-correletion and auto-correlation
              function of a PRN are discussed numerically example in next section.
              4.  C/A PRN Code generation steps
                 As mentioned earlier, the C/A code generator contains two shift registers known as G    and G   . These shift registers each have
              10 cells  generating  sequences of length 1023. The G    register always has a feedback configuration with the polynomial as
              Equation 6. Table 2 show entire sequence of 1,023 chips is repeated 1,000 times each second, resulting in a “Chip-Rate” of 1.023
              MHz or one phase switch (chip) every one-millionth of a second. Every 1023rd period, the shift registers are reset with all ones,
              making the code start over. After code generation, the codes are combined with the navigation data through Gold polynomial2
              adders.

                                                 Table 2. Code Generation from G 1
               C/A PRN code                     G   :   F(X) = 1 + X + X                 result   Output of G 1


                 Generation                                                                      fed input to G2
               TFSR          1    2     3     4     5     6     7      8      9     10
               Step_01       1    1     1     1     1     1     1      1      1      1                 1
                                        1                                            1   1+1=0
               Step_02       0    1     1     1     1     1     1      1      1      1                 1
                                        1                                            1   1+1=0
               Step_03       0    0     1     1     1     1     1      1      1      1                 1
                                        1                                            1   1+1=0
               Step_04       0    0     0     1     1     1     1      1      1     1                  1
                                        0                                           1     0+1=1
               Step_05       1    0     0     0     1     1     1      1      1     1                  1
                                        0                                           1     0+1=1
               Step_06       1    1     0     0     0     1     1      1      1     1                  1
                                        0                                           1     0+1=1
               Step_07       1    1     1     0     0     0     1      1      1     1                  1
                                        1                                           1     1+1=0
               Step_08       0    1     1     1     0     0     0      1      1     1                  1
                                        1                                           1     1+1=0
               Step_09       0    0     1     1     1     0     0      0      1     1                  1
                                        1                                           1     1+1=0
               Step_10       0    0     0     1     1     1     0      0      0     1                  1
                                        0                                           1     0+1=1
               Step_11       1    0     0     0     1     1     1      0      0     0                  1
                                        0                                           0     0+0=0
               Step_12       0    1     0     0     0     1     1      1      0     0                  0
                                        0                                           0     0+0=0
                                                                                                             8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications


               Step_n-1      … ….      …    …     …     …     …     …        …      …      …           0
                                       …                                            …      …
               Step_1023     … …       …    …     …     …     …     …        …      …      …           …

                     Similarly, Table 3 shows how to combine the code from the G1 polynomial and generate PRN codes using G2 for all
              satellites individually. This table shows only the first GPS satellite.
                                     Table 3. Code Generation using G 2 only for SV # 01 and SV # 32

            C/A PRN code               G   = 1 + X + X + X + X + X + X                Out to   result   Output of G2






             for SV # 01                                                              next
               TFSR       1    2    3     4     5     6     7       8      9     10

              Code state   ١   ١    ١     ١     ١     ١     ١       ١      ١     ١              1
              Step_01          1    1                 1             1      1     1            ∑ 6=0
             For SV # 01       1                      1                                       1+1=0        0
             For SV # 32                  1                                1                  1+1=0        0
              Code state   ٠   ١    ١     ١     ١     ١     ١       ١      ١     ١              1
              Step_02          ١    ١                 ١             ١      ١     ١            ∑ 6=0
             For SV # 01       ١                      ١                                       1+1=0        0
             For SV # 32                  1                                1                  1+1=0        0
              Code state   ٠   ٠    ١     ١     ١     ١     ١       ١      ١     ١              1
              Step_03          ٠    ١                 ١             ١      ١     ١            ∑ 5=١
             For SV # 01       ٠                      ١                                       ٠+1=١        0
             For SV # 32                  1                                1                  1+1=0        1
              Code state   ١   ٠    ٠     ١     ١     ١     ١       ١      ١     ١              1
              Step_04          0    0                 1             1      1     1            ∑ 4=0
             For SV # 01       0                      1                                       ٠+1=١        1
             For SV # 32                  1                                1                  1+1=0        0
              Code state   0   ١    ٠     ٠     ١     ١     ١       ١      ١     ١              1
              Step_05          1    0                 1             1      1     1            ∑ 5=١
             For SV # 01       1                      1                                       1+1=0        1
             For SV # 32                  0                                1                  0+1=1        0
              Code state   1   0    ١     ٠     ٠     ١     ١       ١      ١     ١              1
              Step_06          0    1                 1             1      1     1            ∑ 5=١
             For SV # 01       0                      1                                       0+1=1        0
             For SV # 32                  0                                1                  0+1=1        0
              Code state   1   1    0     ١     ٠     ٠     ١       ١      ١     ١              1
              Step_07          1    0                 0             1      1     1            ∑ 4=0
             For SV # 01       1                      0                                       1+0=١        1
             For SV # 32                  1                                1                  1+1=0        0
              Code state   0   1    1     0     ١     ٠     ٠       ١      ١     ١              1
              Step_08          1    1                 0             1      1     1            ∑ 5=١
             For SV # 01       1                      0                                       1+0=١        0
             For SV # 32                  0                                1                  0+1=1        0
              Code state   1   0    1     1     0     ١     ٠       ٠      ١     ١              1
              Step_09          0    1                 1             0      1     1            ∑ 4=0
             For SV # 01       0                      1                                       0+1=١        1
             For SV # 32                  1                                1                  1+1=0        0
              Code state   0   1    0     1     1     0     ١       ٠      ٠     ١
              Step_10          1    0                 0             0      0     1            ∑ 2=0
             For SV # 01       1                      0                                       1+0=١        1
             For SV # 32                  1                                0                  1+0=١        1
             Step_1023    …  …      …    …     …     …     …     …        …      …              …          1
                                                                                                             9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications


                     The  results  of  the  G 1  polynomial  code  are  fed  as  input  to  the  second  G 2  polynomial.  In  addition,  Figure  7  show
              combinations of GPS satellites for C/A code generation that there is a unique combination for each satellite to generate the C/A
              code. Figure 9 shows the output combinations of the G1 and G2 polynomials to generate a unique code for each satellite.














                      Figure 9. The combinations of the G1 and G2 outputs to generate a unique C/A code for each GPS satellite.
                                        Table 4. C/A PRN code Generation for SV#01 and SV#32


                                                          (     ) ∩ (     )

                                Output   Output G 2 for   Output G 2 for   C/A PRN code for   C/A PRN code for
                                  G 1      SV#01         SV#32            SV#01              SV#32

                     Step_01      1           0            0                1                  1

                     Step_02      1           0            0                11                11


                     Step_03      1           0            1               111                110


                     Step_04      1           1            0               1110               1101

                     Step_05      1           1            0              11100              11011


                     Step_06      1           0            0              111001             110111

                     Step_07      1           1            0              1110010           1101111


                     Step_08      1           0            0             11100101           11011111

                     Step_09      1           1            0             111001010         110111111


                     Step_10      1           1            1            1110010100         1101111110

                     Step_1023    1           0            1         1110010100…….01     1101111110…10

                     As shown in Table 4, the C/A PRN codes are generated for the two satellites No. 1 and 32 GPS in ten steps, which are
              different and unique to all satellites. These codes are generated and repeated in 1023 strings of PRN code per microsecond for
              each GNSS satellite. Afterward, The GPS carrier’s waves could have been modulated in a variety of ways to carry the binary
                                                                                                            10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications


              codes, the 0s and 1s that are the codes. In any case, the most commonly used spread spectrum modulation technique is known
              as binary phase shift keying (BPSK). This is the technique used to create the NAV Message, the P(Y) code and the C/A code.
              The binary biphase modulation is the switching from 0 to 1 and from 1 to 0 accomplished by phase changes of 180º in the carrier
              wave. PRN codes are a sequence of zeroes and ones, each zero or one referred to as a “chip”. These codes are combined and
              modulated with the navigation data and sent to the ground.
              5.  Gold code polynomial for other GNSS satellites systems

                  In  the  all  GNSS  systems,  the  structure  of  PRN  codes  generation  is  conceptually  similar,  while,  the  form  of  using
                  mathematical equations in the production of these codes is slightly different. Gold code generator polynomial for BeiDou
                  satellites systems are as Equations 10 and 11 [12]:





                                   (  ) = 1 +    +    +    +    +        +                                            (10)
                                    







                                   (  ) = 1 +    +    +    +    +    +    +    +                         (11)
                                   
                  With initial states
                                                         (0) = {0,1,0,1,0,1,0,1,0,1,0}
                                                     (0) =   
                  The range codes are different from GPS even for the same taps, because the polynomials and their initial states are different.
                  In similar, gold code generator polynomial for GLONASS satellites systems are as Equations 12 and 13 [6, 12]:



                                                 (X) = 1 + X + X                      (12)
                                               G


                                                 (X) = 1 + X + X                      (13)
                                               G

              6.  Conclusion
                 In  this  research,  not  only,  the  PRN  codes  generation  for  GNNS  satellites  using  different  polynomials  is  presented  and
              discussed but also, this paper demonstrates a practical application of mathematics in the Geomatics and engineering. The GNSS
              uses of satellites to provide autonomous Geo-spatial positioning. The GNSS satellites continuously transmit signals at two or
              more frequencies. These signals contain pseudorandom noise (PRN) codes and navigation data to allow users to compute both
              the  travel  time  from  the  satellite  to  the  receiver  and  the  satellite  coordinates  at  any  time.  Each  satellite  within  a  GNSS
              constellation has a unique PRN code that it transmits as part of the C/A navigation message. This code allows any receiver to
              identify exactly which satellite(s) it is receiving.
                 The PRN codes have special mathematical properties which allow all satellites to transmit at the same frequency without
              interfering with each other. These codes also allow precise range measurements between satellite and user receivers. PRN codes
              generator contains two shift registers known as gold polynomials. To the all GNSS systems, the structure of the PRN code
              generation using polynomials is conceptually similar, while, the form of using mathematical equations in the production of these
              codes is slightly different. The PRN code generator contains two shift registers always has a feedback configuration with the
              polynomials equations. They is set by choosing specific tap outputs and combining them with exclusive OR operation. The shift
              registers, which are used for code generation, can be described by polynomials. The essential qualities of the PRN sequences are
              defined by the correlation measures. Two infinite random sequences should be uncorrelated. The closer a given PRN sequence
              comes in a truly random sequence, the better the PRN sequence is. In this research, PRN codes generation of GNNS Satellites
              using  different  polynomials  is  presented  and  discussed.  Furthermore,  this  paper  demonstrates  a  realistic  application  of
              mathematics in the Geomatics and engineering.

                  References
              [1]    D. Harris, L. Black, P. Hernandez-Martinez, B. Pepin, J. Williams, and w. t. T. Team, "Mathematics and its
                     value  for  engineering  students:  what  are  the  implications  for  teaching?,"  International  Journal  of
                     Mathematical Education in Science and Technology, vol. 46, pp. 321-336, 2015.
              [2]   W. Lechner and S. Baumann, "Global navigation satellite systems," Computers and Electronics in Agriculture,
                     vol. 25, pp. 67-85, 2000.
              [3]    M. S. Grewal, A. P. Andrews, and C. G. Bartone, Global navigation satellite systems, inertial navigation, and
                     integration: John Wiley & Sons, 2020.
              [4]    L. Winternitz, "Introduction to GPS and other Global Navigation Satellite Systems," 2017.
              [5]    C. Shi and N. Wei, "Satellite Navigation for Digital Earth," in Manual of Digital Earth, ed: Springer, Singapore,
                     2020, pp. 125-160.
                                                                                                            11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Modern Geomatics Technologies and Applications


              [6]    R. B. Langley, P. J. Teunissen, and O. Montenbruck, "Introduction to GNSS," in Springer handbook of global
                     navigation satellite systems, ed: Springer, 2017, pp. 3-23.
              [7]    C. J. Hegarty, "GNSS signals—An overview," in 2012 IEEE International Frequency Control Symposium
                     Proceedings, 2012, pp. 1-7.
              [8]    J. Awange, "Modernization of GNSS," in GNSS Environmental Sensing, ed: Springer, 2018, pp. 17-24.
              [9]    S. Wallner, J.-A. Avila-Rodriguez, G. W. Hein, and J. J. Rushanan, "Galileo E1 OS and GPS L1C pseudo
                     random noise codes-requirements, generation, optimization and comparison," in Proceedings of the 20th
                     International Technical Meeting of the Satellite Division of The Institute of Navigation (ION GNSS 2007),
                     2007, pp. 1549-1563.
              [10]   S.  Thoelert,  J.  Furthner,  and  M.  Meurer,  "GNSS  survey-signal  quality  assessment  of  the  latest  GNSS
                     satellites," in Proceedings of the 2013 International Technical Meeting of The Institute of Navigation, 2013,
                     pp. 608-615.
              [11]   C. J. Hegarty, "A simple model for GPS C/A-code self-interference," NAVIGATION, Journal of the Institute
                     of Navigation, vol. 67, pp. 319-331, 2020.
              [12]   J. Xie, H. Wang, P. Li, and Y. Meng, "Overview of Navigation Satellite Systems," in Satellite Navigation
                     Systems and Technologies, ed: Springer, 2021, pp. 35-66.
              [13]   S. Wen, W. Guan, Y. Wu, C. Yang, H. Chen, Z. Zhang, et al., "High precision three-dimensional iterative
                     indoor  localization  algorithm  using  code  division  multiple  access  modulation  based  on  visible  light
                     communication," Optical Engineering, vol. 55, p. 106105, 2016.
              [14]   M. M. Hafidhi, E. Boutillon, and C. Winstead, "Reliable gold code generators for gps receivers," in 2015 IEEE
                     58th International Midwest Symposium on Circuits and Systems (MWSCAS), 2015, pp. 1-4.
              [15]   M. B. Mollah and M. R. Islam, "Comparative analysis of Gold Codes with PN codes using correlation property
                     in CDMA technology," in 2012 International Conference on Computer Communication and Informatics, 2012,
                     pp. 1-6.
              [16]   H. N. Viet, K.-R. Kwon,  K.-S. Moon, and S.-H. Lee, "Simulation model  implementation of GPS IF signal
                     generator," in 2017 International Conference on Information and Communications (ICIC), 2017, pp. 306-310.
              [17]   B. P. Kumar and C. S. Paidimarry, "Development and analysis of C/A code generation of GPS receiver in
                     FPGA and DSP," in 2014 Recent Advances in Engineering and Computational Sciences (RAECS), 2014,
                     pp. 1-5.




































                                                                                                            12]]></page></pages></Search>